the fire
Festival I had not heard about this
until really just a few weeks ago and
when I heard about it I was so blown
away that I knew I would be preaching on
it the fire Festival let me read to you
just
for a few
moments it was supposed to be the
greatest party ever thrown
so they called it the fire Festival fire
meaning it was going to be hot you get
the the the the meaning
fire Billy McFarland CEO of fire media
Inc and rer J Ru had been flying to the
Bahamas landed their plane on a deserted
island on their way to the Bahamas and
they later discovered that this island
that caught their attention was Norman's
cave also known as great
euma the former private island of an
Infamous
Kingpin the plan was immediately hatched
that they were going to throw a dream
party on the island as a promotional
event for their media
business the owners of the island agreed
to rent it out with the strict condition
that the
Kingpin connection should not be
mentioned under December 12th 2016
Kendall Jenner and other influencers
paid by fire media simultaneously posted
to their Instagram feed an image of an
orange
square with a stylized logo of flames
clicking the logo opened a promotional
video showing Bella Hadid and other top
models running around on this tropical
beach text with the video promised an
immersive music music experience two
transformational weekends on the
boundaries of the impossible this was
the beginning of the fire festival's
promotional
campaign the video immediately went
viral in 48
hours tickets were sold
out schedule for the two weekends in
April and May of 2017 the event sold day
tickets from $500 to $1,500 and VIP
packages including airfare and luxury
luxury tent accommodations for
12,000 how much did I
say customers were promised
accommodations in modern eco-friendly
domes meal from celebrity chefs the
final advertised lineup was for more
than 30 groups including push tiger
designer Blink 182 major laser
disclosure and many more this was
supposed to be the party of the
century but there was one
problem the festival's promotional
material said that the festival would be
held on a remote private island that
once belonged to a drug
trafficker when the owners of the island
saw that advertisement they immediately
pull the
plug so that the party would no longer
be held on that
island fire media fire media now when a
jam had to search for a new
island and they finally secured one
another island in the Bahamas a remote
island listen carefully altered Maps
were now included in the promotional
material to make it appear that the new
island they settled on was the island
that they had promoted in the
video local workers were busy preparing
Roker Point scattering sand over its
rocks and attempting to improve a road
to a narrow nearby Beach where they
built some Cabanas and some swing
sets do you catch what's going on
here fire media is now in a jam because
they have sent out this promotion
promising one thing and the island that
they were going to have the song has now
been removed from the
picture and instead of coming clean they
try to cover up the
lie with another lie
one article writes the festival quickly
sold out and everything seemed a bit too
good to be true which later showed
itself to be more than true what
followed was an epic tale of disaster
where basically everything was revealed
to be
untrue Villas were in reality disaster
relief tents from
FEMA with dirt floors and mattresses
that were soaking wet because the night
before the event was to take place it
rained only poor quality cheese
sandwiches were provided as food and
things quickly escalated into Mayhem and
looting ensued as the reality of the
situation started to Dawn on the
festival gors
during this time or before the event
there began to be voices of warning
because people began to see things that
weren't adding
up towards the the the last moments
before this event took place musicians
started pulling out and investors who
were realiz who realized that that that
the the the the the people putting on
this Festival were lying or or just not
being truthful began to pull their
Investments and so now they really have
nothing but the promotion had already
gone
out another article says this writing
from New York Magazine one of the event
organizers later noted that since at
least mid-march there were significant
problems with the planning and at one
point it was agreed to outright cancel
the 2017 Festival in favor of working to
a perfect one in
2018 these plans however were revoked at
the last minute with the decision to go
on with the event as
planned let's just do it and be Legends
man one of the organizers is reported to
have
said the people who had bought tickets
were never
told of
what they were coming to see
imagine spending
$112,000 to pay
$122,000 to be
scammed have you ever
fallen for a
lie Mr McFarland was eventually arrested
for you guessed it
fraud have you ever been
sold a
lie have you ever seen the advertisement
and thought man I want
that and when you got the thing that
you thought you were going to get you
realize that you have just
been
scammed and they started making jokes
about this you know pray for the victims
of fire Festival I mean there were no
there was no Calamity you know no one
got injured but when the people got
there it was total chaos it descended
into total chaos and so people started
making fun of people who actually had
$112,000 to spend to go to a concert and
you know so you know the jokes were pray
for the
survivors of fire
Festival come with me to Isaiah 12:
14 Isaiah 12 and verse4 and once again
the message I have for you this morning
is really very simple but it is a
message that we need to hear Isaiah
12 verse
14 I'm sorry Isaiah chapter 14 rather
Isaiah chapter
14 and verse
12 speaking of Lucifer the Bible says
how art thou fallen from Heaven oh
Lucifer's son of the morning how art
thou cut down to the ground which did
weaken the Nations for thou H has said
in thine heart I will Ascend into heaven
I will exalt my throne above the stars
of God I will sit also upon the Mount of
the congregation in the sides of the
north I will Ascend above the heights of
the clouds I will be like the most
high the organizers of this Festival
wanted Fame they wanted to be known for
throwing the largest party and it was
all in part to promote their business
and let me suggest to you that Lucifer's
fall from Heaven was because he wanted
Fame he wanted to be like
God and as a result of this he was cast
out where was he cast out to he was cast
out to the Earth and when he was cast
out to this earth we we understand that
when he was cast out to this earth that
he got an idea
his idea
was this is a beautiful
planet and I would like to
throw a
fire
Festival I would like to throw a
party on this island I mean this
planet and so he goes to the owner or at
least the sub owner
Adam I invite you you and Eve to do what
eat from this tree of life or from this
tree of knowledge of Good and
Evil and we know that the Bible tells us
that Adam and Eve eat from the tree and
as a result what have they just
done they have just passed
ownership to
Satan the the the island the Earth is
now his you see when Adam and
Eve clicked on Satan's
advertisement the tree of knowledge of
Good and Evil when they when they
clicked on that sin immediately went
viral you
understand that nothing goes
viral like sin
the Bible tells us that all have what
sinned and fallen short of the glory of
God and beloved I believe that that that
when Satan brought sin into this
world he basically began
advertising for great
party a party like none other a party
where you get to have all the
fun in the
world did you catch what I just said all
the fun where in the
world and you see that's what Satan is
busy doing now he is busy advertising
for this great party this great Festival
listen carefully this great fire
Festival
that is coming beloved listen to me
Satan wants you at that
final
fire
festival and so what does he
do he
advertises hey look at the
world doesn't it look like they're
having
fun don't you want the world in fact you
remember when Jesus came to this earth
and the Bible tells us that when when
Satan met Jesus in the wilderness
Matthew 4:8 the Bible says again the
devil taketh him up into an exceeding
high mountain and showeth him all the
kingdoms of the world and the glory of
them and said unto them all these will I
give thee if thou will fall down and
worship me that's the price of a
ticket what does the song
say you can
have all this world but give
me Jesus
Satan advertises hey look listen you
realize that it was because of the
models that fire media had recruited
that when when the when the influencers
when the when the people that everyone
knows the social media uh uh socialites
when when they put it out on their
Instagram and Facebook everybody else
was like oh wow look at those names we
want to be
there you really realize that that's how
Satan
operates he uses influencers to to steal
our children from
us he uses influencers to to to take our
young people our young adults and yet
even our old adults he uses influencers
to say man look at the world doesn't it
look like that is an amazing party to be
at don't you want to be a part of it who
would want to miss out on this fun look
at them
they look like they're having
fun beloved our response should ever be
you can have what all this world but
give me who give me
Jesus you see beloved I just imagined
that as that party was going that as as
that party was being planned and people
were you know bragging and boasting
about how they're going to spend
$122,000 to go to this party where all
these top models are going to be and
it's going to be just an amazing weekend
drinking and all this kind of stuff and
I can imagine them boasting and I can
imagine others kind of feeling like man
we don't get to be a part of
that not
realizing that they were being set up to
be
deceived and and so Satan offers offers
he says to us listen man the thing that
everyone is doing that every everyone
wants to be the place where everyone
wants to be that's the place to be but
the Bible says enter ye in at the
Straight Gate for what wide is the gate
and Broad is the way that leadth to
destruction and many there be which go
in their
acts beloved just because the world
looks like it's having fun doesn't mean
they are having fun
just because the world looks like it is
partying and and and and and and having
fun and and and just you know doing what
they want to do and living life how they
want to live and you're thinking man you
know here I am being a Christian trying
to be right trying to live right and man
life is so boring for me just because
look at how much fun they're having
every time I turn the TV on look at that
it just looks so inviting and so
appealing but let me tell you something
beloved you know what Satan does he's a
master of hiding
truth when Jesus was in the wilderness
and the Bible says that Satan showed him
all the glories of the world let me ask
you a
question is there glory in this world of
sin how is it that Jes Satan is showing
Jesus all the glories of the
world what he has done is he has
photoshopped the world and swn it to
Jesus hey look doesn't this look
appealing if you actually read a a
spirit of prophecy on this account it
actually says that Satan hid the traces
of sin to make the world look better
than it
was all this false advertising that fire
media put out deceived the people into
thinking something that was not actually
the case you see beloved according to
Ezekiel 28 Satan is a
merchandiser he has merchandise he sells
you you think of merchandising you know
you think of that guy on the
street Satan is that merchandiser hey
hey come here check this out party going
on G to happen at the end of time you
should
go fire Festival I'm telling you man
it's going to be hot
beloved that he is right about it's
going to be
hot and so he makes it look appealing so
everyone is preparing to go to the party
not realizing what the party actually
is Satan is a seller of
Lies so so he sells us the lie that we
are worthless so we may as well or we
are unwanted so we may as well or your
sins are too great for God so for God to
forgive so you may as well or the broad
road is the way that leads to fun so you
may as well or you only live once YOLO
which is a
lie because everybody's going to Live
Twice everybody's going to have to
answer for the things done in the body
he'll lie yeah you shall not surely die
he'll lie you're not not good enough so
you may as well throw in a towel all his
lies are designed to get you to the
party but there's good
news because you see while
Satan believed and felt yep I bought the
planet it's now mine something
happened that pulled the planet from out
of his
grip and that thing that happened that
pulled the planet from out of his grip
is that Jesus Christ came to this world
and said yeah you can't use this planet
for your
party why do you have to take this
planet from me I'm going to die to
redeem this
planet Jesus said in John 12:31 and 32
now is a prince of this World cast out
and the very next verse he says and I if
I be lifted up will draw all men from
the fire Festival y'all are feeling
me I will draw all men to me so when he
says I will draw all men to me it's
because all men had gotten the flyer had
gotten the advertisement that there was
going to be a fire festival and everyone
was was was deceived going towards that
festival and Jesus says Hey Hey Hey
listen I'm telling you I'm a voice of
warning and the festival that Satan is
talking about you don't want to be at
and when Jesus gave up his life on the
cross he redeemed this world so that it
no longer belong to
Satan but
beloved that put Satan in a
jam what am I going to do
now this planet is no longer mine I'm
defeated I Was Defeated at the cross
[Music]
so I'm going to keep advertising and I'm
going to keep pushing as if I'm still in
control and beloved many of us are
believing the lie that Satan is still in
control this is still his Planet he's
still the prince of the power of the air
of this world and we live life believing
the
lie not realizing not understanding that
the Bible says that the devil knows that
his time is
short and instead of coming clean and
telling the people yes uh you know
Christ is Lord yes uh I was wrong yes H
I have fallen from Grace instead of
coming clean and and and and telling the
people he is lying no he's going to keep
up the LIE keep up the facade and the
question is will you be
duped especially when there is a voice
voice of warning out there in the voice
of Jesus
Christ will you heed his
voice you see beloved what makes the
party look appealing to
us we read it in our scripture reading
this
morning God doesn't tempt anyone does he
but a man is tempted when he is drawn
away of his
own own
lust and say knows that if he can show
us the right
advertising but like man that party
looks
good and I want to go to
it well love the Bible tells us that the
wages of sin is what is
death the wages of sin is death so
listen beloved listen
carefully the
cross mess
up Satan's party
plans that's what the cross did it
totally threw Satan's plans out of whack
it totally destroyed his plans in fact
we might say that because of the cross
it rained on Satan's
party and you might not understand what
I mean when I say it rained on Satan's
party so let me break down a little bit
further you remember that when Jesus
died 50 days later was the day of
Pentecost and on a the day of Pentecost
what happened it
rained yeah yeah it rained the Holy
Spirit but but that's the it rained
fire beloved listen to me why did it
rain fire because you know the same you
have to
fight fire
Satan expects the fire Festival to draw
you oh man I want to go to that party oh
yes it looks like it's going to be fun
oh and he gets that fire going in you
you get what I'm saying how many of you
remember when you used to be in
sin cuz you're looking at like sin what
is
that right listen to me guys listen
carefully you are never calm in
sin
sin is exciting to the old
man yeah oh man when I was drinking oh
and we get we get that fire in
us oh man when I was doing this thing oh
man when we were out in the streets
fighting oh man when we were living out
life oh man it was the so so Jesus is
trying to tell us listen if you want to
have power over Satan's fire you have to
fight fire with
fire that means the same kind of fire
you used to have for the world you must
now have for Jesus Christ you have to
have that same oh Jesus
yes none of
us watching or being at a place of sin
sits there
like no we are excited about our
sin so so so if you're trying to fight
fire with fire should it not be that we
should have the same excitement and more
than we had in the
world beloved we must Fight Fire with
Fire strength for strength fire for fire
because God is trying to show us listen
Satan's pull his advertising is strong
and if you are if you don't have enough
fire to match his fire you will be drawn
to his
fire it's a principle it's a law in
other words beloved
look the fire of God is not burning in
your
heart John the Baptist said said in
Matthew 3:11 I indeed uh uh baptize you
with water unto repentance but he that
cometh after me is mightier than I whose
shoes I not worthy to Bear he will
baptize you with the Holy Ghost and with
fire in other words Jesus realizes that
in order for us to to effectively
withstand the fire Festival we have to
have fire enough to resist that fire
Festival because anything less than this
is not going to
work what I'm trying to say to you is
that if you are
lukewarm
expect to be attending the fire
Festival I'm not telling you
that I'm just telling you if we live a
lukewarm
life
expect to be at that far Festival
because Satan will draw you it's not
enough to just say I know Jesus it's not
enough to say hey I come to church on
Sabbath and I'm here that's not enough
the fire of God must be burning in your
heart you ask Pastor what is the fire of
God it's the Holy Spirit but check this
out beloved in Song of Solomon Chapter
8: 6 the Bible says love is like a veman
flame that cannot be quenched so that
means the fire fire of God is in
actuality the love of
God it is God's love that must be
dwelling in
us so that we love not the world nor the
things that are in the world because the
lust of the flesh the pride of life the
the lust of the eyes all these things
are of the world and if anyone has that
love in their hearts they do not have
the love of God in their hearts in other
words if the fire of the world is in
your heart heart the fire of God cannot
be in your
heart the only way listen the only
possible way to overcome the fire of the
world is to have the fire of God in your
heart and if the fire of God is not in
your heart listen that's why so many of
our young people again and older people
why so many of us end up going to that
fire being drawn to that fire is because
the fire of God is not burning bright
enough in our hearts we have Embers we
have little spark in other words it is
lukewarmness now check this out Jesus
said I know your condition you're
neither hot nor cold you're
lukewarm and he said as a result of this
I will do what spew you out of my mouth
and then you know what the next thing he
says he says behold I stand at the door
and
knock what is he trying to do by
standing at the door and
knocking he's trying to do what come in
why is he trying to come in because he
is the
fire and he's saying when I get into
your heart you're going to be on fire
the evidence that I am in your heart is
that you will be on
fire that's the
evidence so Jesus gives this story in
the in the New Testament in the parable
of this banquet where he he says check
this out come with me you got to see
this look look Isaiah I'm sorry uh Luke
chapter 14 Luke chapter 14 beginning
with verse 14 Luke
14 Luke 14 beginning with verse 14 I'll
read it on the
screen let's go to verse 15 I think it's
it probably starts with verse
15 all right it is not verse 15 uh let's
try verse 16
all right there we go then said he unto
them this is Jesus speaking a certain
man made a great supper and bath many
now pause for a second what's the great
supper that he
made what's he talking about the great
supper okay it's a wedding right and
ultimately where is this leading us
to to heaven right so uh
food great supper
lots of people invited what does that
sound like to
you sounds like a party does that sound
like a festival to
you
so Bible says our God is a
consuming fire the consuming fire
himself is putting on a fire
Festival is that correct but this is not
the same fire Festival we've been
talking about previously this is God
inviting his own to like a real
party we are Marching to Zion why cuz we
want to be at that fire Festival it's a
different Festival
altoe so check this out guys there's two
fire
festivals Satan has
one and God has
one and what Satan is doing is he's
trying to put his advertisement out
there to say oh man you got I'm telling
you you got to be at this party do you
know who's going to be
there a certain man made a great supper
and B
many verse 17 and his servant at supper
time and sent his servant at supper time
to say to them that were bid come for
all things are now ready Verse
18 and they all with one consent began
to make
excuse the first said unto him I've
brought a piece of
ground oh I'm sorry the first said unto
him there's a fire
festival and I must needs go see
it and you can just fill in the B
because everyone else all the other
excuses really boil down to one thing
the love of the world over the love of
God and the parable Ends by saying none
of those men that were invited to my
Feast that were bidden shall enter
in Beloved you got to understand the
reason that we don't respond to God's
fire Festival to God's invitation is
because of the invitation of the
world and the question is do we really
mean those words words you can have all
this
world but give me
Jesus do we really really mean those
words beloved if we do listen we become
a voice of warning if we really mean
those words we become a voice of warning
we become those those people who knew
about the fire festival and knew that
some things were not sounding right and
they began to sound the warning on
social media don't go to this thing
you're going to get played don't go to
this thing it's a deception it's a lie
guess what God needs people just like
that to sound a warning saying hey guys
it might look like fun out there in the
world it might look like everyone's
having a great time but I'm telling you
the end result is not you're not going
to like
it that message Revelation 146 and seven
uh fear God and give glory to him for
the hour of his judgment is come and
worship him that made Heaven the Earth
the sea and all that that in them is and
then the next message Babylon is Fallen
the party that you guys are going to is
not what you think it
is come
out don't be a part of
it because listen beloved as we wrap up
listen
carefully when the people arrived at the
scene and they saw these FEMA tant FEMA
they have footage of people on the buses
school buses which should have been a
warning sign to them already what is a
school bus coming doing coming to pick
us up from the airport and everyone's on
the bus is kind of confused and as the
buses get to the location they had
people working day and night trying to
make the location appear as something
that it was not and they failed when the
people got there and they saw white
tents they were like turn this bus
around now but beloved listen to
me
listen at the end of
time that will not be an
option it will be too
late once you are on Satan's bus and the
bus has left its destination there is no
can I get off this bus
now our warning message is to prevent
people from getting on that bus for that
last
ride Lord please open their eyes listen
to me
guys at the End of
Time Satan is going to be arrested for
fraud the Bible says that Revelation
20:1 an angel comes down and puts chains
when you put when you have chains put on
you what have you you've been
arrested Revelation 21 Satan is going to
be arrested for
fraud and beloved just as it rained on
Satan's party on the day of Pentecost so
at the end of time it will
rain because the Bible
says that God will rain fire down out of
heaven
upon those who
responded to Satan's
advertising that will be the
final fire festival for the
wicked beloved while the righteous will
have their own fire
Festival because Revelation 15:1 says I
saw another sign in heaven great and
marvelous seven angels with the seven
last plagues for in them is filled up
the wrath of God and I saw as it were a
sea of glass mingled
with and them that had gotten the
victory over the Beast and over his
image and over his Mark and over the
number of his name stand on the sea of
glass having the harps of
God beloved which fire Festival do you
want to go
to because one is making a lot of
promises that it cannot and will not
keep many of us struggle man which party
which party how long do I want to like
not go to this fire how long do I want
to keep just like turning away from what
what what the world is advertising
because it looks so good listen
guys people lost
$122,000 but what does it profit a man
if he gain the whole
world and
lose his
soul
$112,000 doeses not compare to a
Soul beloved listen to me you got to
fight fire with
fire and you know what for many of us we
are living in a lukewarm
reality and today God is saying I can
turn your fire up